# **David Mulyawan Oktavianus**

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia | +62 851 5507 0838 | david.mulyawan97@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/david-mulyawan | github.com/davdmoo

# **Professional Summary**

Software developer with a skillset in full stack software development and almost 3 years of experience in developing applications for mobile, web, and desktop platforms. Managed to deliver a self-service bus ticketing project in a high traffic international airport. Experienced in Flutter, React, Node.js, payment system integration using QRIS and EDC terminals, and third party backend service integration.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages/Frameworks
  - 1. Flutter
  - 2. Typescript
  - 3. React
  - 4. Express
  - 5. React Native
- Database
  - 1. PostgreSQL
  - 2. MongoDB
  - 3. Firebase Cloud Firestore
  - 4. SQLite

#### Others

- 1. Next.js
- 2. Redux state management
- 3. Bloc state management
- 4. Linux

# **Experiences**

#### Qios Teknologi Indonesia

Staff Programmer (Feb 2022 - present)

- Develop, maintain, and deploy a self-service bus ticketing platform using Flutter, Javascript, and Firebase in a high traffic Indonesian international airport
- Develop, maintain, and deploy a self-service gym membership management platform using Flutter, Typescript, and Firebase
- Integrate QRIS payment with payment gateway and state bank
- Integrate payment using conventional EDC terminals
- Implement Firebase Cloud Messaging for payment notifications
- Integrate with existing third party backend systems
- Implement native Java code for hardware-related use cases using Flutter's platform channel
- Design and implement application error logging using Firestore SDK and Firebase Crashlytics
- Develop and maintain existing frontend codebases using Flutter for web and mobile apps
- Develop and maintain existing backend codebases using Typescript/Express
- Develop unit tests using Jest

#### **Freelance**

Full Stack Developer (2024 - present)

Successfully delivered 1 project for a client in the retail industry

- Developed a Windows-based invoice management app using Flutter, Typescript, and MongoDB, focusing on invoicing and stock management
- Implemented features such as authentication, automated invoice generation, stock tracking, customer management, and monthly reporting
- Managed project timeline using GitHub Projects and successfully delivered within said timeline
- Created and managed monthly database backups
- Integrated Sentry for error tracking

## **Portfolios**

### 1. Slinks (https://slinks.deno.dev/)

A simple link shortener web app to explore HTMX and Deno. Features include light/dark mode, QR code generation for links, and copying into clipboard.

Technologies used: Deno runtime, HTMX, SQLite, Hyperscript

## 2. Personal Site (<a href="https://davdmoo.vercel.app">https://davdmoo.vercel.app</a>)

A simple personal site featuring light/dark mode, server-side generation, built-in analytics, and message board.

**Technologies used**: Next.js, Typescript, SQLite

## 3. rePath (<a href="https://github.com/davdmoo/repath-be">https://github.com/davdmoo/repath-be</a>)

Contributed as the backend lead during Hacktiv8 bootcamp's final project, developing a JSON API using Express and MongoDB. The project aimed to recreate the now-terminated Path social media platform.

Technologies used: Express, MongoDB, Javascript

#### **Education**

#### Hacktiv8 Full Stack Javascript Bootcamp (Sept 2021 - Feb 2022) (Grade 86)

- Learned programming from scratch using Javascript
- Gained hands-on experience in developing APIs, web and mobile applications, and software automated testing
- Developed skills in backend and frontend development using tools such as Express, Jest, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, React, and React Native

#### Padjadjaran University (2016 - 2020) (3.22 GPA)

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry